该死的 你搞什么鬼?
What the hell are you doing?
看好了 我手上有你需要的东西
You know I havewhat you need
到时候我会给你另一半的
And I'll give you the rest
前提是我确认索菲亚 lj
After I know that Sofia, lj
他们都平安无事
They're all safe.
我的书 书呢
My book my book
起来
Get up
这是哪里?
What is this place?
是我们交易的地方 按我们的约定
Where we're gonna make the exchange on our terms.
沿路下去5英里的一个废弃仓库
An abandoned warehouse five miles down the road.
20分钟内 带上我儿子到那儿
Be there in 20 minutes with my son.
他们一定关闭了所有离开 巴拿马城的道路
They must've closed all the roads out of Panama.
爸爸 那我们怎么办?
Papa, what do we do?
惠斯勒还在假装他的那套渔夫言论?
Whistler still pretending he's a fisherman and all this?
如果他不是渔夫 他又是干什么的呢?
Well, if he's not a fisherman, what is he?
我才不管他说什么
I don't care what he says
我根本不认识什么叫迈克・斯科菲尔德的家伙
I don't know anything about this Michael Scofield guy
你确认还要继续撒谎下去吗 费尔南多?
You sure you don't want to change your story Fernando?
我想这是我们分道扬镳的地方
I guess this is where I say good-bye.
抢我的皮卡
Hey my truck
不
No
我们现在该怎么办?
What are we gonna do now?
能借用下手机吗?
Do you have a cell phone?
电话请借我
please
是我女儿 谢谢
It's my daughter thanks
我把他们甩了 赶紧过来接我
I lost them. you need to come and pick me up.
你在哪里?
Where are you?
让我猜猜电话那头是谁
Let me guess.
如果他有什么意外
If anything happens to him
那要看情况了 不是吗?
That depends, doesn't it?
我已经到了你说好的仓库了
I'm at the warehouse, like you said.
你们在哪里?
Where are you?
你想我们还能去哪 在追逐你的伙伴呢
Chasing your buddy where do you think I am?
好吧 何不返回这里
Well, why don't you get back here.
我手上有lj和索菲亚 我准备好做交易了
I have lj and Sofia. I'm ready to do the exchange.
-等我电话 -你说什么?
Call you back. what?
计划搞砸了
The pl's shot.
-她已经到了 -好吧 那现在呢?
She's already there. all right. so now what?
我花了2周时间布置那仓库
It took me two weeks to hook up that warehouse.
我们总能想出对策的
We'll figure something out.
我能修复这一切 也是我正试图做的
I can fix this. that's what I was trying to do.
你打电话让他们来接你
You were calling them to pick you up.
这样就不会再有人受到伤害了
So no one else would get hurt
你真以为我会让别人去冒险吗?
You really think I would put anyone's life at risk?
你早就这么做了
You already ve.
爸爸 我可不想回索纳监狱去
I-i can't goac b to Sona, papa
我回不了头的
I can't
你不会回索纳监狱的
You're not going back to Sona.
问几个问题
A couple of questions
然后就可以走了
and you'll be on your way
我们正在寻找
We're looking for
四个从索纳监狱逃出来的逃犯
four escaped convicts from Sona.
你见过这些人中的哪一个吗
Have you seen any of these men?
很抱歉 我不认识他们任何一个人
Sorry.I don't recognize any of them
你确定吗
You sure?
把车开到这边来
Pull over up there.
我们必须要检查你的车
We're going to have to inspect your car.
但是我以为你是说
But I thought you said
我知道我说了什么
I know what I said.
现在把车开过来
Now pull over.
你想喝水吗?
Do you want some water?
还是打算告诉我迈克・斯科菲尔德哪去了?
Or do you want to tell me where Michael Scofield is?
我不知道他在哪里
I don't know where he is.
知道吗 打从你第一天来这里干活
You know, from the first day you started here,
我就知道这里面有什么猫腻
I knew there was something off about you.
或与我能第一眼就分辨出是否是囚犯
I guess I just know a con when I see one, huh?
或许你能成为当月之星优秀员工
Maybe you'll get to be employee of the month.
我在等着
I'm waiting.
碰头点变了
There's been a change in venue.
噢 很好
Oh, well, well, well.
我终于有机会和幕后总策划交谈了
I finally get to talk to the brains of the outfit.
我们在法兰西广场
We're at the Plaza De Francia.
你认为公众场合就来得更安全
So you're thinking public place, safety in numbers,
有很多目击者来保护你们
Plenty of witnesses to protect you.
在我看来 公众场合 通缉犯 警察
I'm thinking public place, wanted men, police,
众人都可以来指认你
Lots of witnesses to identify you.
10分钟内赶来法兰西广场
Plaza de francia. ten minutes.
单独来
Be alone.
集合所有人
Round everyone up.
这里一片混乱 我们得躲躲
It's anarchy in here we gotta hide
我得帮他
I gotta I gotta help him.
他是这里最糟忌恨的家伙
He's the most hated person in here.
如果我们继续和他手挽手 那我们就
If we start rubbin' elbows with him again, then we're gonna
他给了我容身之所
He gave me a home
他给我的是背部三级灼伤
He gave me third-degree burns down my back
他早就该见鬼去了
He can go to hell
这些都是我亏欠他的
I owe him this much.
你不想帮忙 那就别来
You don't want to help, then don't.
都给我滚开 小毛贼
Get outta here shoo fly
快到了 还有几步
Just a few more steps. it's only a few more.
到家了 就快到了
Then it's home, sweet home.
这地方是我的
This is my house
冷静点
Easy, now.
滚
Get out
得了
Come on
他会害死我们的
He's gonna get us killed.
他能帮我们出去
He's gonna get us out of here.
欢迎
Buenas.
要来点什么?
What can I get you?
汽水
Club soda.
以前来过巴拿马吗
You been to panama before?
第一次来
First time.
你在美国是干什么的?
What did you do back, uh, in the states?
我现在处于过渡期
I-i'm in sort of a transitional period right now.
工作老换来换去的
In between jobs.
真遗憾
Oh. sorry to hear that.
大家都差不多
Yeah, we've all been there.
但我想不久后就会有改观的
I'm sure something will come up before long.
那希望能早点到来
I'm hoping it's right around the corner.
这里
Here.
你不需要这个了
You won't be needing this anymore.
这是干什么的
What's this for?
告诉我关于迈克・斯科菲尔德 的确切消息
You're gonna give me some real information on Michael Scofield.
不然你就等死吧
Or it's gonna be your funeral.
我不知道他在哪
I don't know where he is.
我发誓 我真不知道怎么找到他
I don't know how to reach him, I swear.
哪条路? 你自己选 老兄
Well, which one is it gonna be, papi?
你好 格雷琴
Hello, Gretchen.
惠斯勒在哪?
Where's Whistler?
在我右手边
Over my right shoulder.
知道么 你是第一个从索纳逃出来的
You know, you're the first to ever break out of sona?
他们在哪?
Where are they?
带他们出来
Bring them out.
我和很多的聪明人打过交道
I've worked with a lot of intelligent people
迈克 但是 你是
In this business, Michael, but you
或许 你要是能站到组织那一边
Maybe you wouldn't have to worry about the company trying
就不必担心有人要杀你了
To kill you if you were on their side.
而且他们报酬丰厚
They certainly pay well.
他们就在那
There they are.
把惠斯勒交给我 我就把lj给你
Give me Whistler and I will give you lj.
你敢乱来 我就开枪
If you move, you'rdead.
等候命令
Wait for hand-off.
收到
Roger that.
他搞什么鬼?
What the hell is he doing?
失去目标
I've lost him.
这里不是交易地点
This is not the point
这只是确认下罢了
Of the exchange. this is just a confirmation
看看是否都还活着
That everyone's still alive.
都活着 交换吧
They're alive. let's trade.
5分钟后你会接到电话
You'll get a call in five minutes
到时自会告诉你去哪里
Telling you where to go next.
交易结束后
And when the exchange is over
等lj 也安全了
And lj is safe,
我再跟你好好聚聚
You and I are gonna spend some quality time.
等交易结束
When the exchange is over,
你最好快点逃命
You better run for your life.
打开
Open it.
把油布拿下来
Remove the tarp
我想如果有人爬上我的卡车的话
I think I would have noticed if
我肯定会发现的
someone had climbed on my track
还要我重复
Do I have to repeat
我刚才说的话吗?
everything I say to you?
把那该死的油布揭开
Remove the damn tarp
不然我们就扣留你的车
or we'll impound your track
是肥料
It's fertilizer.
快走吧
Just get out of here.
走
Go.
谢谢 爸爸
Gracias, papa.
还有一站
One more stop.
下面开始暴动了
There's a storm brewing out there in the yard.
去告诉他们
You tell them
尽管来 我不怕他们
Come in. I'm not scared.
我怕
Well, I am.
那东西 还是放下吧
You might want to put that down.
蒂博格
Oh, Teodoro.
真没想到帮我的人会是你
You're the last one I'd expect to see at my side.
我始终站强大这方 老大
I take offense, patron.
我有过很多提鞋的人
I've had many foot-washers.
很多都披着伪善的外衣
Many men have come in with sheep's clothing,
到后来就全部暴露本性了
Only to let the wolf come out.
我不想害你 只是想要帮你
I am not trying to hurt you. I am trying to save you.
帮我?
Save me?
我会死在这
I'm gonna die here.
和我待这儿 就是死路一条
Your life is in jeopardy just being with me.
未必
Not necessarily.
当我刚才被押回来的时候
As I was being escorted back inside today, one of the guards
有一个警卫说 我们有机会买回自由
Offered us a chance to buy our freedom.
如果警卫跟你说 那他就是在骗你
If a guard spoke to you, he was lying.
出去根本不可能
It's impossible to get out.
也许你还没注意到就被警卫毙了
Maybe you've been too busy dying to notice,
但是外面来了个新军官
But there's a new colonel outside those gates.
小小的索纳监狱现在看管
Little suzy Sona ain't playing so hard
没那么严了 有钱就行
To get no more. she has her price.
我们需要一笔钱
And we gonna need some money.
没有
No.
那么你就死在这吧
Then you will die in here.
迈克
Michael.
古代博物馆的大厅
The lobby of the museum of antiquities.
为什么
Why?
因为惠斯勒在那
Because that's where Whistler is.
你太精明了
You're overthinking things.
我以前见识过太多了
I've seen it too many times before.
第一个计划失败 你就开始虚张声势了
The first plan goes to hell and then you start tap-dancing,
相信我 计划终归会流产
And, trust me, it always ends badly.
你有5分钟
You have five minutes.
真不可思议
Unbelievable.
你知道该怎么做
You know what to do.
有什么高兴的
What's so funny?
你呀
You.
以为你比我叔叔更聪明?
Thinking you can outsmart my uncle.
走
Walk.
金属探测器
Metal detectors.
我想在这里我们会建立起一种信任
And here I thought we were building a circle of trust.
过来一楼的西南角
Come to the southwest corner of the first floor.
好
Fine.
这样就够了
But that's it.
不要再玩花样了
No more stops on your guided tour.
如果我没有带着惠斯勒走出这个地方
If I don't walk out of here with Whistler,
我就抹了lj的脖子
I'm gonna snap lj's neck.
当然 我说到做到
And yes, I can do it.
我们行动吧
Here we go.
每个人都准备好了吗
Is everyone in position?
收到
Roger that.
最后一瓶朗姆酒
Last bottle of rum.
再见了 老大
Good-bye, patron.
他们要多少钱
How much do they want?
5万
$50,000.
不可能
No.
我们可不是在提华纳为了一块地毯讨价还价
We're not in tijuana haggling over a ket.
我们是为了你的命
We're talking about your life.
即使我可以 弄到那笔钱
Even if I could find the money,
我能让谁给带进来
Who could I trust to bring it in?
就有那么一个人
There is one person.
你怎么认识詹姆斯的
How do you know James?
你在挑战我最后的防线吗 快走
You're working my last nerve. move your ass.
放松点
Relax.
每个人都给我冷静点 我们都会走出去的
Everybody stays cool and we will all walk out of here.
我们一得到lj 你就得到惠斯勒
As soon as we get lj, you get Whistler.
lj先到我们这边来
But lj ces to us first.
去吧
Go ahead.
lj
Lj.
感谢上帝 你还好好的
Thank god, you're safe.
坐标呢
What about the coordinates?
你说过的 你见到惠斯勒以后
You said first thing you would do once
就只要剩余的坐标
You had whistler was to get the rest of the coordinates.
她不是开玩笑吧?
Is she serious?
我们走出这里的时候
I'll give her exactly whathe wants
我会给她她想要的
When we get out of here.
但是亲爱的 这里不安全 我们得走了
But darling, it's not safe. we need to go.
我要看看他们
I want to see them.
索菲亚 快走吧
Sofia, come on.
我们离开这里
Let's get outta here.
等下 等下 等下
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
索菲亚
Sofia.
你把那些数字写在一张纸上了
You otwrthose numbers on a piece of paper.
在索纳我给了她一半
I gave her half at sona.
我答应现在要给她另一半的
I promised to give her the other half now.
我知道我说过的话 等会儿再谈这个好吧
I know what I said, and we'll discuss it later.
真相大白了是吧
Come on. welcome to the real world.
我早厌烦了
I'm sick of jumping through hoops
整天把你的公主当宝贝似的照顾
To keep your princess in a bubble.
-是时候该走了 -这是我俩之间的事
It is time to go. this is between us.
坐标在哪里 苏珊?
Where are the coordinates, Susan?
没有坐标这回事好了吧
There are no coordinates.
索菲亚
Sofia.
赶紧
Come on.
索菲亚
Sofia.
詹姆斯
James.
别闹了
Stop kidding yourself.
该走了
It's time to leave.
你还留在这里干什么
And what the hell are you still doing here?
如果我是你的话 武器带不进来
If I were you and I couldn't bring weapons inside,
我肯定会叫几个特工守在门口
I'd have agents at every exit
等我们一出去就开枪
Ready to shoot as soon as we stepped outside.
所以你从哪个门出去都无所谓
Well, then it really doesn't matter
是吧
What exit you take, does it?
我从那个门走哦
I'm gonna go out that door.
也许你们该从那个门走
Maybe you should take that door.
事实上
Actually,
紧急情况下那个门会被锁上
That door is locked in the event of an emergency.
什么紧急情况
What emergency?
这个
This one.
我们走出去 一起
We're all walking out of here.
很戏剧化哦 自己把警察找过来
That's very dramatic, calling the cops on yourself.
看来你真的很想回索纳哦
You must really want to go back to Sona.
他们不是来抓逃犯的 格雷琴
They're not looking for a con, Gretchen,
他们是来抓小偷的
They're looking for a thief.
我跟你说过的一切都是为了保护你
Whatever I told you, it was always to protect you.
让我解释吧 你肯定会理解我的
You'll understand, if you just let me explain.
躺下
Lie down
你们这么做 就因为我认得迈克・斯科菲尔德
All this because I knew Michael Scofield?
告诉我他在哪
Tell me where he is.
我不知道
I don't know
马上躺下
Lie down now
就算我知道
Even if I knew
喂
Yes?
好的
All right.
马上到
It'll be here shortly.
拿到钱之后
Now that we have the money,
怎么送到狱警手里
How do we get it to the guard?
不送给狱警
We don't.
什么意思 不送? 我们说好
What do you mean, we don't? we-we-we were supposed
买通狱警的啊 这是计划啊
To bribe the guard that was the plan
这才是计划
This is the plan.
这是正经事
This is business.
你们所有人 都会理解我
And you, of all people, should understand.
帮我把他按住
Help me hold him down.
你在说什么?
What the hell you talking about?
快点
Do it.
Do it
蒂博格
Teodoro
蒂博格 蒂博格
Teodoro Teodoro
反正我死是早晚的事
It's just a matter of time, anyway.
但是死在这两个小偷手里
But from one thief to another
给我点尊严吧
out of respect,
痛快点
Make it quick.
只要你不反抗
If you don't fight me,
我就会让你痛快点的
I will.
走好 朋友
Adios, homey.
这里有问题
Over here.
怎么了
What's the problem?
在他口袋里发现这个
I found this in his pocket.
你能解释一下
Would you care
这是什么吗
To explain this?
我不知道
I've got no idea what it is.
在博物馆纪念品店买的
It's from the gift ship.
这是塑料的
It's plastic.
现在我们能走了吗
Now, if you'll excuse us.
又怎么了?
What?
别动
Stay where you are.
-为什么? -你的身份证呢?
Why? where is your identification?
索菲亚
Sofia
爸爸 爸爸你不能这样
Dad, dad you can't do this.
不能留下来
You can't do this.
警察会起疑了 我们必须快离开
The cops are gonna start asking questions. we gotta go.
詹姆斯 你想怎样? 如果你回去
What are you gonna do, James? you go back there,
就会被抓 这对我们都没好处
You'll get arrested, and that won't do any of us any good.
凭你对她的所作所为我就该杀了你
I ought to kill you right now for what you've done to her
够了
Enough
我这样做都是为了把你救出来 明白吗
I did what I had to do to get you out, period
别忘了什么才是生死攸关 詹姆斯
You remember what's at stake, James.
停车 我不能丢下她
Stop the van. I can't leave her.
她已经抛弃你了
She already left you.
我不会扔下她
I'm not gonna leave her
爸爸 你得离开
Dad dad, you've got to go
我会守着她
Hey, I'll stay with her
我保证
I promise.
你得走了
You've got to go.
爸爸?
Dad?
走 走
Go go
谁来帮帮我?
Hey, could I get some help?
你都准备好了吧?
Do you have everything?
我的书不见了
The book is gone.
什么叫不见了?
What do you mean, gone?
是真的吗?
Is it true?
勒齐
Lechero
他
He's
他真的
He's really
还好
Yeah.
我怎么给你这些?
How do you want me to give you this?
那些警卫
The guards, they won't
-不会再让我进去了 -我只想得到
Let me in anymore. I only want
我需要的东西
What I asked for.
先等几天
Hold on to the rest for a few days.
如果你想
If you were to consider leaving
携款逃跑 那
With all that, well
我会非常生气的
I just want you to know I'd be very cross with you.
众所周知
I've been known to have
如果有人背叛我
A bit of a temper problem
我会大发雷霆的
When betrayed.
不会的
No.
说定了
A deal's a deal.
你为我做了那么多
You've done so much for me.
我向你保证
You have my word.
等等
Wait.
不 不
No, no.
没关系
It's okay.
我会等着你
I'll wait for you.
你准备好了吗?
You ready?
迈克・斯科菲尔德在哪里?
Where is Michael Scofield?
好了
Stop.
这不管用
This is not working.
过几分钟他就..
A few minutes more
把他拖出来
Pull him out there.
扔进去
Toss him inside.
等等
Espera
如果是他
If it's him
你就问清楚他们在哪里
You're gonna find out where they are,
不然我会自己接
Or I'm gonna answer it myself,
让他们听见你中枪而死的惨叫声
So they can hear you scream when I blow your head off.
喂?
Hello?
感谢上帝 苏克雷
Sucre. thank god.
你没在船那里出现 我还以为
When you didn't show up at the boat, i
我很抱歉 伙计
I'm really sorry about that, papi.
我的工作有点麻烦
I got into a little bit of trouble here at work
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
是的
Yeah.
你在哪里?
Where are you?
你们救出LJ了吗?
You guys get lj?
是的 他很好
Yeah. he he's fine.
林肯怎么样?
What about Linc?
他好吗?
Is he okay?
他没事
He's fine.
你真的没事?
Are you sure you're all right?
我还好
I'm fine.
一切都顺利
It all worked out.
我要去坐公车了 伙计 保重
I'm about to catch the bus, papi. take care.
好啊
Okay.
杀了我吧
Kill me if you want.
你错了 伙计
Wrong, papi.
我会让你求生不得 求死不能
You're gonna wish we had.
勒齐已经死了
Lechero is dead
我在此将他埋葬
I come before you now to bury the man
并不是要赞扬他什么
not to praise him,
因为他在这里残酷的统治
For there is nothing praiseworthy
根本就没有值得赞扬之处
About his rule here.
让我们其中的一员发号施令?
Having one of our own dictate to us?
那可不符合自然规律
Well, that's just not the natural order.
在这里都是平等的
All cons are equal
我这里还剩余一些
I have the last remnants
勒齐剥削来的财富
Of Lechero's cruel empire in my hand.
我曾渴望加入他们之中
An empire which I willingly participated in
也曾目睹他们的恶行
And witnessed first-hand.
这些钱 都是压榨你们而来
Money made off of your backs
全是出自你们的辛劳
And off the backs of your family
现在这些是你们的了
It's yours.
我要说的是
And I'm here to tell you,
我要将它们物归原主
I'm giving it back.
物归原主 弟兄们
Giving it back, brothers.
全都还给你们
Giving it back
还给你们
欢迎回家 伙计
Welcome home papi.
我们都是平等的
We're all equal.
-她会没事的 -太好了
She's gonna be okay. good.
迈克叔叔
Uncle Mike, um
我一直想等到我们安全以后再给你
I wanted to wait until we were safe to do this,
可是
But
在莎拉和我被囚禁的屋子里我找到了这个
I found this in the room where Sara and I were he
我想也许你需要它
I thought you might want to have it.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
谢谢
Thanks.
索菲亚怎么样了?
How's Sofia doing?
-她很好 -好的
She's good. good.
警察很快会离开
The cops will be leaving soon.
然后你就能上去看看她了
You can go up and see her, then.
太好了
Good.
她想让我告诉你
She wanted me to tell you something.
在她公寓的
She said there's something
床底
In her apartment underneath her bed.
-有一些关于惠斯勒的情报 -我不感兴趣
Something about Whistler. I'm not interested.
是什么?
What is it?
迈克 已经结束了
Michael, this is over.
到此为止了
It's done.
我问 那是什么?
I said,"what is it?"
你迟到了
You're late.
我的饮料你付钱
And you owe him for my drinks.
能让我们单独呆会儿吗
Give us a minute?
出手挺大方
It's a nice tip.
她付了我钱
She handles the money.
加入吗
You in?
若她能付比那更多的钱
She'd better be able to handle a lot more than that.
因为如果她真如你所想
Because if she has done
那样做了 那么莎拉
What you think she has Sara
她才是突破点
she's the weak link.
斯科菲尔德会找到她
And he will find her.
接着他会发现你
And then scofield will find you
和我
and me.
那时我不会为你所做的一切负责
And I'm not paying for your mess.
加入与否?
Are you in or are you out?
我加入
I'm in.
林肯?
Linc?
没事
Yeah.
把枪给我
I need your gun.
谢谢
Thanks.
杰森 利夫
"jason lief."
你听说过这家伙?
You heard of this guy?
没有 但如果他对惠斯勒很重要的话
No, but if he's important to Whistler,
那对我也很重要
He's important to me.
冷静点 迈克
Whoa, slow down, Michael.
-我要去找惠斯勒和格雷琴 -别 别这样
I get to Whistler, I get to Gretchen. no, no, no, no.
这是唯一的机会了 我们和lj可以
This is the one chceanou, me and lj have of sticking toge
他们杀了莎拉 林肯
They killed Sara, Linc.
我很难过
I'm sorry about that.
你知道 听着 伙计 我
You know listen, man, i
我已经竭尽所能
I did everything I could, you know.
我所能做的一切
Everything.
我全明白
I know you did.
但我必须去
But I gotta go.
谢谢
Thanks.